Gabriel Ramos

Rio de Janeiro, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil



gabriel.o.c.ramos@gmail.com



+5521983580220



linkedin.com/in/gabrielocramos

Summary

Software Developer with great experience in mobile development, using React Native and Redux Saga; and web development, using React.js, bare HTML/CSS/Sass, PHP and JavaScript ES6/7/8, as I have also worked in many projects using Wordpress and C#/.NET.

Furthermore, as working in mobile development using React Native, I have learned a little of Android and iOS native languages in many cases when React Native updates got some incompatibility with the current native files, so I had to fix it up by updating manually those files.

My 3 years of experiences include companies applications development, in-app services development and e-commerce apps. My current job is an e-commerce development for the largest international e-commerce Company in Latin America, called Americanas S.A. This is the most famous brand group behind giant Brazilian e-commerce names, such as Americanas.com, Submarino.com, Soubarato.co, Shoptime.com and Ingresso.com.

In search of more experience and self-development, to improve my tech skills and to be part of great projects. And I guess this Company is a great opportunity for me to achieve that. I am always opened to learn and adapt my skills - as I have been doing it all along my career - so I know I can fit well for this position, and I can do much for this Company.

Experience



Software Developer

americanas s.a.

Jul 2021 - Present (4 months +)

- App and Web Developer of the international e-commerce division.
- Developer of the new Soub! mobile app in React Native.
- Working with React Native for e-commerce app development.

loomer

Front End Supervisor

Loomer Tech

Feb 2021 - Jul 2021 (6 months)

- Responsible for a better Scrum Methodology use.
- The header of e-commerce integration of apps.
- Creator of better apps architecture.
- Made the new front-end layout of the Company apps that turned it more professional looking.
- Integration between the applications and the API database.
- Responsible for the front-end work of all the company apps.
- Front-end developer of web based systems.
- Responsible for the company website UX development.
- · Worked to solve complex problems using the latest in Cloud, Mobile, and Web Technologies.
- Supervision and help for Junior and internship developers.

- Worked well independently and on a team to solve problems.
- I helped the company achieve high goals and received bonuses with cash promotions and bigger participation.

IT Technical Mananger

Milk & Fruit

Jan 2019 - Jun 2021 (2 years 6 months)

- Provided superior design skills and a strong understanding of computer software.
- Planned and developed written policies and procedures for computer operations.
- Identified client needs and suggested appropriate services to enhance client experience.
- Helped to achieve a consistent look and visual theme across the website by promoting uniform fonts, formatting, images, and layout.
- · Coordinated mailings, marketing materials, and website content.
- Remained knowledgeable in new standards, technologies, and trends in website development.
- · Managed the maintenance of machines.
- Performed scheduled updates, routine maintenance calls, and made repairs when necessary.

Front End Developer

Inventa Produtos Digitais

Dec 2018 - Jun 2021 (2 years 7 months)

- Freelancer developer since 2018 for the company, being completely hired in 2020.
- Full-stack development for web based .NET systems.
- Front-end developer of all mobile and web applications.
- Front-end developer of all websites.
- Effectively translated client requirements into application designs and system requirements.
- Provided effective troubleshooting and remediation for web applications.
- Worked to solve complex problems using the latest in Cloud, Mobile, and Web Technologies.
- Successfully identified, diagnosed, and fixed website problems, including broken links, typographical errors, and formatting issues.

Palestrante em sessões

OBA! Planetário Itinerante

Aug 2017 - Aug 2020 (3 years 1 month)

- Attended workshops and classes to further my professional skills.
- Motivated students to learn and participate.
- · Speeches all around the country about Astronomy and

Astrophysics in many universities, schools and scientific events.

Education



Bacharelado e Licenciatura, Física 2016 - 2020

Centro Universitário UniCarioca

Bacharelado, Ciência da Computação 2017 - 2017

Colégio Apollo 12

Ensino Médio, Técnico em Eletrônica 2014 - 2015

Licenses & Certifications

- **Lean Six Sigma White Belt Certification** americanas s.a.
- Segurança da Informação americanas s.a.
- Lei Geral de Proteção de Dados (LGPD) americanas s.a.
- React Native The Practical Guide [2021 Edition] Udemy UC-51be0a9c-6404-4695-b5bc-84227a6a475a

Skills

Aplicativos móveis · Desenvolvimento web · JavaScript · Programação de computadores · Matemática • Tecnologia da informação • React Native • CSS • HTML • Adobe Photoshop